Guide to the World War II Pamphlet Collection 1937-1991 (bulk 1939-1945)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- Great Britain - Military: Education (in English), 1944; Education in the British Army. New York: British Information Services, 1944. (Box 5/1)
- Great Britain - Military: Force 136 (in English), 1991; Tsang, Jan N., and Kim H. Tan. Force 136 (1). Pulau Pinang: Jawatankuasa Sejarah Lisan dan Perpustakaan, Universiti Sains Malaysia, 1991. (5/2)
- Great Britain - Military: Navy & Merchant Navy (in English), 1940-1945; The War at Sea: Some Striking Facts and Figures: July & August 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; The British Merchant Navy. New York: British Information Services, 1945. (Box 5/3)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: British Broadcasting Company (in English), undated; Britain Speaks: Regular Programs to America, Overseas Service of the B.B.C. New York: British Broadcasting Company, n.d. (This pamphlet offers a schedule of radio programs effective February 16 for American audiences.); Britain Speaks... New York: British Broadcasting Company, n.d. (This pamphlet offers a schedule of radio programs effective September 29 for American audiences.) (Box 5/4)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: "Cables from Britain" (in English), 1940; Cables from Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/5)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: "The European Background" (in English), 1943; The European Background: Extracts from the Press of Enemy Occupied and Neutral Countries. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/6)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: "The Listener" (in English), 1951; The Listener. London: British Broadcasting Corporation, 1951. (A weekly, serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 19/2)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: "The New Statesman and Nation" (in English), 1943; The New Statesman and Nation: The Week-End Review. London: The Cornwall Press, Ltd., 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 19/3)
- Great Britain - News Coverage: "Radio Times" (in English), 1950-1951; Radio Times. London: British Broadcasting Corporation, 1950-1951. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 19/4)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Against Communism (in English), undated; Why Die for Stalin? n.d. (Box 5/7)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1939-1940; The Outbreak of War: 22nd August-3rd September, 1939. New York: British Library, 1939.; Hitler's Words and Hitler's Deeds. England: s.n, 1940.; Einzig, Paul. Europe in Chains. Harmondsworth, Middlesex, Eng: Penguin Books, 1940.; Halifax, Edward F. L. W. Challenge to Youth: Abridged from Address Delivered by Lord Halifax at Oxford, February 27th, 1940. England: s.n, 1940.; Planning for War & Peace: Ten Leading Articles Reprinted from the Times. London: Times Pub. Co., Ltd, 1940.; It's Different Now....I have change my mind. London: The Daily Herald, 1940.; The Issue: No. 2. London: Macmillan & Co., 1940. (This is part of a serial publication titled "Round Table War Pamphlets."); Smuts, Jan. Prospects of War and Peace: Reprinted from "The Listener," July 25, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (Box 5/8)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Against Germany (in English), 1945; Britain against Germany: A Record in Pictures. New York, N.Y: British Information Services, 1945. (Box 5/9)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Against Imperialism (in English), undated; The U.D.C. and the War. London: The Union of Democratic Control, n.d. (Box 5/10)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Against Japan (in English), 1944-1945; First Blows: Britain's Fight against Japan. New York, N.Y: British information Services, 1945.; Britain Versus Japan. New York: British Information Services, 1944. (Box 5/11)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at Germany (in German), 1943-1944; Das Ende Einer Division. [A Division Written Off.] P.W.D./SHAEF, 1944. (This leaflet, and many others like it, was published by the Psychological Warfare Division, which produced propaganda for the Allies. The leaflets targeted German soldiers and was dropped by U.S. or British aircraft in areas of Europe where German troops were stationed.); Generale Proklamieren Friedensregierung. [Generals Proclaim Peace Government.] P.W.D./SHAEF, 1944. (This leaflet, and many others like it, was published by the Psychological Warfare Division, which produced propaganda for the Allies. The leaflets targeted German soldiers and was dropped by U.S. or British aircraft in areas of Europe where German troops were stationed.) (This particular pamphlet discusses the assassination attempt on Hitler by Claus von Stauffenberg.); Soldatenpflicht. [Prisoners of War (America).] P.W.D./SHAEF, 1944. (This leaflet, and many others like it, was published by the Psychological Warfare Division, which produced propaganda for the Allies. The leaflets targeted German soldiers and was dropped by U.S. or British aircraft in areas of Europe where German troops were stationed.) (This particular pamphlet is written to American soldiers being held in German prison camps.); Doldatenfrauen und Ehefrauen! Witwen und Mutter! Der Bolschewismus Droht. 1943. (This leaflet was likely published by the Psychological Warfare Division, which produced propaganda for the Allies. The leaflets targeted German soldiers and was dropped by U.S. or British aircraft in areas of Europe where German troops were stationed.) (This particular pamphlet was likely dropped by balloon and is a repint of an article in the "Frankfurter Zeitung" which discusses the change of a divorce law and how it would affect soldiers and their wives.) (Box 5/12)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at Germany (in German), 1944; Nachrichten Für Die Truppe. No. 68. Nendeln: Kraus Reprint, 1944. (extremely fragile; "Nachrichten" was a British publication, containing factual news and propaganda. The intended audience was German soldiers. Both British and American Air Force troops dropped these pamphlets in areas of Europe where German troops were stationed.) (Box OS 23/1)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), undated; "The Tools of Victory": Photographs of Britain's Weapons [order form]. New York: British Library of Information, n.d.; Second World War: British White Papers, Blue Books, etc. obtainable from the British Library of Information [order form]. New York: British Library of Information, n.d.; The Home Front in Art: War Pictures [order form]. New York: British Library of Information, n.d.; The Fire Fighters of London in Action [order form]. New York: Garden City Publishing Co., n.d.; Shelter at Home [order form for Air Raid Precautions Handbooks]. New York: British Library of Information, n.d.; The Battle of Britain [order form]. New York: Doubleday, Doran and Company, n.d. (Box 5/13)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1940; Buchan, John. My America: Reprinted from Pilgrim's Way. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (Box 5/14)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1940; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/15)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/16)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1941. (This is a serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/17)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1941. (This is a serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/18)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1941. (This is a serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/19)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Britain Today. Oxford: University Press, 1942. (This is a serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 5/20)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941 and undated; Halifax, Edward F. L. W. Speech by the Right Honourable the Viscount Halifax, British Ambassador to the United States, English Speaking Union, New York, April 15, 1941. New York: British Library of Information, 1941. (2 copies); Maps of Britain. New York: British Information Services, n.d. (Box 5/21)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1940; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/1)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1940; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/2)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/3)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1941; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/4)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/5)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/6)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Bulletins from Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/7)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1942; Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 6/8)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943; Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 7/1)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943; Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 7/2)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943; Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 7/3)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943; Picture Charts of Britain at War. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (Box OS 19/5)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1943-1944; Another 50 Facts About Britain at War. New York: British Information Services, 1943.; A People at War: Life in Britain Today. New York: British Information Services, 1943.; A Picture of Britain: Background of a People. New York, N.Y: British Information Services, 1944.; John Britain. New York: British Information Services, 1944.; 5 Years of War. New York: British information services, 1944. (Box 7/4)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1944; British Information Services. [Serial publication, 1943-1945]. New York: British Information Services, 1944. [(Discusses a variety of war-time domestic politics issues including: machinery reconstruction, lend-lease, and education.) (Not all issues available.)] (Box 7/5)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1945; British Information Services. [Serial publication, 1943-1945]. New York: British Information Services, 1945. [(This serial publication discusses a variety of war-time domestic politics issues including: veteran information, currency, and general elections.) (Not all issues available.)] (Box 7/6)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Aimed at the United States (in English), 1945; Whitechester, England: A Town at War. New York, N.Y: British Information Services, 1945. (Box 7/7)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: "British Library Leaflet" (in English), 1941; British Library Leaflet. New York: British Library of Information, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 7/8)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Calendars (in English), 1944-1946; 1945 [calendar]. New York: British Information Services, 1944. (A pictorial calendar with photos of the war.); B. I. S. Wishes You a Merry Christmas and a Very Happy New Year 1947 [calendar]. New York: British Information Services, 1946. (A pictorial calendar with photos of post-war Great Britain.) (Box 7/9)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Food Supply (in English), 1940-1941; The British Farmer at War. London: H.M. Stationery Office, 1941.; Food for Europe: Reproduced from the "London Economist" August 17, 1940, by kind permission of the Editor. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (Box 7/10)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Labor (in English), 1939; Marchbank, John. This Is the People's War. New York: British Library of Information, 1939. (Box 7/11)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Lend-Lease (in English), 1944; Britain and the Common Pool. New York, N.Y: British Information Services, 1944. (Box 7/12)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Letters (in English), 1940; Letters from Home. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Letters from Home: Second Series. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; A British Flier Writes His Mother. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. [(Also published under the title: "An airman's letter to his mother.") (Reprinted by the British Library of Information, New York, from the New York Times, June 22, 1940.)] (Box 7/13)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Pro-Imperialism (in English), 1940; De, Courcy K. Memorandum of Information on Foreign Affairs and the World Crisis, No. 20. London: Imperial Policy Group, 1940. [(A serial publication; only Issue 20 available, accompanied by a map.) (Also attached is a letter, written to the president of the University of Montana.)] (Box 7/14)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Social Services (in English), 1940-1943 and undated; 50 Facts About Social Services in Britain. New York City: British Information Services, 1943.; Owen, Arthur D. K. The British Social Services. London: Longmans, Green & Co, 1940.; Progress in Freedom. New York City: British Information Services, 1943. (pictorial); Britain's Social Services in War-Time. New York: British Library of Information, 1941.; Education in England and Wales: Some Questions Answered. New York: British Library of Information, n.d. (Reproduced from typewritten copy.) (Box 7/15)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: Speeches (in English), 1940-1943; Churchill, Winston. Mr. Churchill's First Speech As Prime Minister: Delivered in the House of Commons, May 13th, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Prime Minister Churchill's Address Before the House of Commons, Tuesday, June 4, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; The Voice of Britain: "We still have time - but not much time." 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech by the Prime Minister, Mr. Winston Churchill, Delivered in the House of Commons, June 18, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill on the Taking of the French Fleet: Delivered in the House of Commons, July 4, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill, July 14, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Halifax, Edward F. L. W. We Shall Prevail: Speech Broadcast by Viscount Halifax, Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, July 22, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (This speech references the editorial "Twelve O'clock" in Box 18, Folder 7.); Churchill, Winston. Britain's Strength: Speech by the Prime Minister, the Rt. Hon. Winston Churchill, in the House of Commons, August 20, 1940. New York: The British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister, Mr. Winston Churchill, to the People of France, October 21, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech by the Prime Minister, Mr. Winston Churchill, on War Problems Facing Britain Delivered in the House of Commons, November 5, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill to the Italian People, December 23, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill, February 9th, 1941. New York: The British Library of Information, 1941.; Churchill, Winston. Speech by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill to the Pilgrim Society, March 18, 1941. New York: British Library of Information, 1941.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister Mr. Winston Churchill, April 27, 1941. New York: British Library of Information, 1941.; Churchill, Winston. Speech Broadcast by the Prime Minister, Mr. Winston Churchill, May 10, 1942. New York: British Library of Information, 1942.; Winston Churchill, Prime Minister: A selection from speeches made by Winston Churchill during the four years that Britain has been at war. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (Box 8/1)
- Great Britain - Propaganda: War Effort (in English), 1940-1943; British Youth Answers the Call. New York City: British Information Services, 1943.; War-time Britain. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Bevin, Ernest. The War and the Workers. New York, N.Y: British Library of Information, 1941. (Box 8/2)
- Great Britain - Propaganda, Patriotic (in English), 1940-1941 and undated; Harlow, Vincent T. Commonwealth in Arms. London: Printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode Ltd, 1940.; Tawney, R H. Why Britain Fights. London: Macmillan & Co, 1941.; We Shall Win Because--. London: L.T.A. Robinson Limited, n.d. (Box 8/3)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1941; Peace Aims: British Official Statements: a Chronological Record, from September 2, 1939, to September 24, 1941. New York: British Library Information, 1941. (Box 8/4)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1942; Britain Plans: British Official Statements, Volume II. New York: British Information Services, 1942. (Box 8/5)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1943; Britain Looks Ahead: British Official Statements, Volume III. New York: British Information Services, 1943. (Box 8/6)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1943; Post-war Planning in Britain: Unofficial Post-War Planning, 1939-1943. New York: British information Services, 1943. (2 copies) (Box 8/7)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1944; Winning the Peace: Extracts from Speeches by Members of the British Government. New York, N.Y: British Information Services, 1944.; Britain and Tomorrow: British Official Statements, Volume IV. New York: British Information Services, 1944. (Box 8/8)
- Great Britain - Reconstruction (in English), 1945-1946; Britain's Future in the Making: New Measures in a Living Tradition of Social Progress. New York, N. Y: British information services, 1945.; Plan for the New Coventry: From Disorder and Destruction Order and Design. Watford, England: H. & S. Ltd, 1945.; Buildings of Britain, Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow. New York: Distributed by British Information Services, 1945.; John Britain-Postwar. New York, N.Y: British information Services, 1946. (Box 8/9)
- Hungary - Reconstruction (in English), 1948; Hevesi, Endre [editor]. Hungarian Bulletin, No. 38. Budapest: N.p., 1948. (Box 8/10)
- India - Nationalism Argument (in English), 1940-1944; Raman, T A. India and the War. New York: British Library of Information, 1940. (Mr. T.A Raman's speech broadcast by the British Broadcasting Corporation, June 11, 1940.); Raman, T A. India against Aggression: Speech Broadcast in the United States by the National Broadcasting Company from London, June 30, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Hope, Victor. India: Statement made in India by the Viceroy (the Marquess of Linlithgow). New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Amery, L S. India: I. India and the War, Statement by the Governor General of India, the Most Hon. the Marquess of Linlithgow, Simla, 8 August 1940. Ii. India in the Commonwealth, Speech by the Secretary of State for India, the Rt. Hon. Leopold C.m.s. Amery, Before the House of Commons, August 14, 1940. New York: British Library of Information, 1940.; Amery, L S. The Indian War Effort: A Speech Delivered in the House of Commons on November 20, 1940. New York, N.Y: British Library of Information, 1940.; Haward, Edwin. A Picture of India: Its History, People, and Government. Malaya [Singapore]: The Department of Information and Publicity, 1941. (second and revised edition.); Raman, T A. What India Wants. New York: British Library of Information, 1941.; Amery, L S. Speech by the Rt. Hon. Leopold C.m.s. Amery, Secretary of State for India: Delivered in the House of Commons, August 1, 1941. New York: British Library of Information, 1941.; India: Speeches Delivered at a Tea Given by the American Outpost in London on May 6, 1943, in Honour of the Rt. Hon. Leopold Amery, M.p., Secretary of State for India. London: Unwin Bros, 1943.; India: Progress in Government. New York: British Information Services: 1944. (Box 8/11)
- India - Nationalism Argument: Religious Response (in English), 1940; Higginbottom, Sam The British Government in India. United States: s.n, 1940. (Reprint of Chapter VII of "The Gospel and the Plow.") (Box 8/12)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1940; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 8/13)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1940; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 9/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1940; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1940. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 9/2)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1941; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 9/3)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1941; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box 9/4)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1941; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1941. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 20/1)
- India - News Coverage: "Indian Information" (in English), 1942; Indian Information. New Delhi: Bureau of Public Information of the Government of India, 1942. (A serial publication; not all issues available.) (Box OS 20/2)